Ross Franey (he/him)

Software Engineer

Profile

Hi! I'm a Software Engineer for Qualtrics Dublin, with 2.5 years of professional experience. Prior to this I graduated top of my class in Dublin City University with a 1st Class Honors.

I have professional experience using Python, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Clojure and C++. From a personal perspective, I have experience in Ruby, GO, and Haskell.

Education

Bs. Software Engineering, Dublin City University

September 2015 — June 2018

- 4.0 GPA
- · 1st Class Honor
- Graduated top of class

Employment History

Software Engineer at Qualtrics, Dublin

August 2018 — Present

- Scope and deliver complex, varied projects as the lead or only engineer, for global clients such as Google, L'Oreal, HSBC and Adidas.
- Received 2 quarterly "exceeds expectations" performance ratings.
- [Java] Work on a large scale SMS distribution product sending 4 million weekly messages, adding 700% performance increase and an improved queuing system.
- [Python] Received internal award for developing "Survey as Code" System, allowing users to manage surveys through Git.
- [NodeJS + Python] Designed and delivered a data privacy API for Adidas.
- [PHP] Delivered user provisioning service to Google.
- [React] Worked with our developer platform product team to allow clients to create their own automatons through the User Interface.

Software Engineer Intern at Cellusys, Dublin

March 2017 — September 2017

- Serving telecom clients in Java / Clojure based projects
- Delivered feature to distinguish between Arabic / Non-Arabic messages
- Gained experience with Puppet / Docker / Jenkins

Personal Projects

ML trading platform - Python / Java

Present

- Python / Django Web Application and Android application
- Used AWS DynamoDB and MySQL for storage
- Connects to multiple Cryptocurrency and FX exchanges

Details

ross.franey3@mail.dcu.ie

Links

Portfolio Github Linkedin

Skills

Scoping & System Design

Data Structures & Algorithms

Technical Writing / Design Documentation

AWS Lambda, S3, DynamoDB

Databases (MongoDB, SQL, DynamoDB)

Hobbies

- Coding challenges / contests
- Volunteer with refugee groups
- Personal finance, investing
- Sports (GAA)

Motion Detection Security System - Java

September 2018

- Java Android Application using a Raspberry Pi.
- Connected webcam to Raspberry Pi and used motion detection library to capture movement.
- Send alerts to your phone with images of the intruder.

Asynchronous Messenger Chat Applet

September 2017

Peer to Peer chat room practicing asynchronous programming in Java.